Marshall Reisman papers concerning George Nakashima
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Marshall Reisman papers concerning George Nakashima
1959-2010
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Reisman, Marshall
0.2 linear feet
The Marshall Reisman papers concerning George Nakashima are dated 1959-2010, bulk 1972-1989, and comprise 0.2 linear feet. The papers include letters, correspondence, annotated sketches, photographs, financial records, and printed material related to commissioned works by woodworker and sculptor George Nakashima for art collector Marshall Reisman.
Provenance
Donated by the Dorothy and Marshall M. Reisman Foundation through Robert Falter, trustee, 2010.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Marshall Reisman (1914-2009) and his wife Dorothy (1914-2008) were both art collectors from Syracuse, NY. They commissioned furniture and other objects from George Nakashima (1905-1990).
Scope and Content Note
The Marshall Reisman papers concerning George Nakashima are dated 1959-2010, bulk 1972-1989, and comprise 0.2 linear feet. The papers include correspondence, letters, annotated sketches, receipts, photographs, financial records, and printed material related to commissioned works by woodworker and sculptor George Nakashima for art collector Marshall Reisman.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 3 series:
Series 1: Annotated Sketches, 1972, 1989 (Box 1; 1 folder)
Series 2: Letters and Related Financial Records, 1959-2001 (Box 1; 5 folders)
Series 3: Printed Material 1962-2010 (Box 1; 2 folders)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects-Topical:
Collectors and collecting--New York (State); Woodworkers; Sculptors; Art commissions
Types of Materials:
Photographs; Sketches
Names:
Nakashima, George, 1905-1990
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Annotated Sketches, 1972, 1989, Series 1:; (Box 1; 1 folder)
  Annotated sketches of furniture and objects designed by Nakashima for Reisman.
  - Annotated Sketches, 1972, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters and Related Financial Records, 1959- 2001, Series 2:; (Box 1; 5 folders)
  Letters and photographs concerning furniture and other objects designed by Nakashima for Reisman. Related financial records include recceipts, estimates for restorations, invoices, and shipping records.
  - Letters and Related Financial Records, 1959-2001 (Box 1, Folder 2-6)
- Printed Material, 1962-2010, Series 3:; (Box 1; 2 folders)
  Printed material includes articles about the artist as well as the March 16, 2010 auction catalog featuring the Reisman collection.
  - Printed Material, 1962-2010 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)